Love is the best teacher.
Pliny the Younger, "Epistulae"
You brought the newest issue?
Yes, I'd love to hear your thoughts on it.
You've already read it?
They've all been so good, after all.
Once you finish it, feel free
to return it to the library.
By the way, I'm sorry to be blunt,
but are you the one who changed Ryuen-kun?
What makes you think that?
I just put the puzzle pieces together.
I'm sorry to be so forward with you.
I know you don't like to
talk about things like that.
If I lost a friend with similar
interests over something like this,
I'd really regret it.
But I thought that if I didn't take that
step, we might not make any progress.
Any progress?
I'm sorry.
I don't even know what I'm trying to say.
Um, did you hear how our
Class D fought in the final exam?
I don't condemn your method, at least.
But a plan that could get your
opponent hurt is clearly wrong.
If you knew that, why didn't you stop it?
You really think he'd listen
to what I have to say?
Would you take a message
to Ryuen for me, Hiyori?
Of course.
I'd like to talk to you.
Can you come now?
I'll be waiting at Café Pallet in Keyaki Mall.
Let me know if you can't make it.
"Come now"? What in the world does he want?
3rd Season
Classroom
of
the
Elite
Classroom of
the Elite
Hey.
What do you want?
Sit, why don't you?
If people see us having tea together,
won't they spread weird rumors?
Were you with someone just now?
Yeah. Hiyori.
Hiyo—
We both like reading, so we talk a lot.
Oh? You use her given name, huh?
And you've got stuff in common?
Oh, yeah?
Look, I don't care who you're friends with.
What did you want?
Sorry, I forgot.
What?! What's wrong with you?!
I'll email you again if I remember.
This is ridiculous.
I'm out of here.
Meeting up in the bathroom?
Very tasteful of you.
I heard how you shone during the final exam.
Can I assume you're back in business, then?
Who can say? Maybe it was just a whim.
So? What do you intend to do next?
Don't think you can win by
going around as a double agent.
You damn snake.
Double agent?
Sorry, but I'm not content to
be in with just two classes.
Kanzaki?
He was just begging for an audience with you.
And in return, you get an in with Class B?
Did you really think
Kanzaki would go for that?
Oh, he will.
Won't you?
Hashimoto, I don't trust you at all.
But I do believe I can use you.
You heard him.
So? Here to describe to
me the taste of defeat?
Just so you know, the dirty tricks you
used won't work on Class B again.
Please. You're just Ichinose's bootlicker.
What do you expect to do?
It's true that I've spent this
year as Ichinose's supporter.
But if Ichinose can't bring
herself to do what's necessary...
I'll take my own approach to
fighting an enemy like you.
Ayanokoji!
Hey!
Hey, Ayanokoji!
I thought up the perfect
way to get to Class A!
You should join our class!
Huh? Where's this coming from?
If Ryuen-san and Ayanokoji teamed
up, they'd be unbeatable.
Sakayanagi and Ichinose
would be a breeze to beat!
I'd certainly give you my best.
Hey... Are you serious?
See? See?
We'd love to have you!
But it can't really happen.
Where would you get the twenty million
points needed for me to change classes?
Besides, it's more fun to have
him as an enemy than as an ally.
You and Ryuen are both weirdos.
Maybe you're right.
You'll catch a cold just standing there.
Ayanokoji-kun?
You can be rather forceful, Ayanokoji-kun.
You seemed like you didn't
want to go back to your room.
It seems like you're always
there when I'm feeling low.
Feel free to share your
troubles with me again.
I can't.
I've already relied on you enough.
To impose on you any longer...
It would just be too pathetic.
You don't trust me?
It isn't that!
I think I trust you more
than anyone else right now.
Even though I'm an
enemy from another class?
I don't like to throw
around the word "enemy."
You might not be my ally,
but I can trust you.
Talking to Horikita-san
earlier made it clear.
She's grown so much in this past year.
Same with Ryuen-kun and Sakayanagi-san.
The other class leaders are
getting stronger and stronger.
I wonder if I'll be able to beat them.
I'm scared.
Where will I be in a year?
What do I do?
Ayanokoji-kun?
You're a mysterious person, Ayanokoji-kun.
Hey, Ichinose.
Will you meet with me again,
like this, a year from now?
Just you and me.
Focus on moving forward for one
whole year, then meet with me.
Can you promise you'll do that?
I...
But by then, what if I...
What if our classes...
That doesn't matter.
There are words I want to say to you now,
and I promise that I'll say them to you then.
I promise, too.
I'll spend this year
fighting with all I have!
And I'll aim for Class A!
The future isn't certain.
But...
If Ichinose ever seems
about to fall into ruin...
I'll deal the killing blow.
3rd Season
Classroom
of
the
Elite
Classroom of
the Elite
Being here takes me back.
Forget that crap.
What's with this message from Hiyori,
Shiina Hiyori
Ryuen Kakeru
A message for Ryuen-kun
This is from Ayanokoji-kun.
"I could have more easily and safely won
five matches in the special exam."
For the rest, please talk to Ayanokoji-kun.
Ayanokoji?
It means just what it says.
You could've done it better and safer, huh?
I'd be sad if you messed up
and had to leave the school.
Big words from the man
who lost to Sakayanagi.
I did lose, yes.
And as I was the team captain,
I can't make excuses.
Yeah? Don't give me that crap.
You beat me, so you could've beat Sakayanagi.
Were you just not even trying?
Or maybe there was something
beyond your control...
Is that it?
So, what are you going to do next?
Enjoy my time off, of course.
And once I get tired of that,
I think I'll warm up by crushing
Ichinose and Sakayanagi.
And if anyone's going to expel you...
It's going to be me!
Impressive.
That's the best a surprise attack gets me?
You do have potential.
Try to mature more effectively, Ryuen.
Since when did you become my teacher?
If Class B had found proof of what
you did, you'd have been screwed.
If you stay at your current level,
we'll never have a rematch.
Don't leave obvious tracks.
Under the circumstances,
I'll take your shitty advice.
But one day, I will crush you.
I wouldn't mind being crushed by you.
You're going on lots of dates
with Ike-kun lately, huh?
Huh? It's not like that with him!
You don't have to deny it!
I'm curious, too!
I told you, it's not like that!
Oh, really?
You're blushing, though.
You're red all the way to your ears!
Seriously, knock it off!
It's nothing!
Want me to buy you a crêpe after this, then?
Sorry, got something to do.
I'm taking off early! See you later!
S-Sure.
Karuizawa-san seemed a little down, huh?
Did something happen to her?
Speaking of, Sato-san,
how did things go with Ayanokoji-kun?
Huh?!
That's right!
You were thinking about
how to ask him out, right?
Promise you won't tell anyone?
Of course we do!
You bet!
R-Right...
What? He turned you down like that?!
K-Keep it down!
What is he, stupid or something?
I think... Ayanokoji-kun likes Karuizawa-san.
F-For real?
Yeah.
And I think Karuizawa-san
might like Ayanokoji-kun, too.
I'm trying to forget, but...
I always thought Karuizawa-san
had higher standards, like me.
But... Ayanokoji-kun's a quality guy, too.
Really? He's just a fast runner, right?
Yeah, but... it's more than that!
What did you call me out here for?
Well?
What would you think of returning to
your father after this spring break?
No. I like this school.
I'm afraid your life here might
just get harder if you don't.
Why don't we have a game?
A student from the White Room will
be mixed in with the incoming class.
If you can ascertain which student it is
by the end of April, I will withdraw.
You're not the only success we've had.
That student will be the
one to put an end to you.
Understood.
But there is one thing that
I can say with confidence.
There is no one from the White
Room who is superior to me.
Those eerie eyes with such
darkness within them...
You're the spitting image of your father.
Ayanokoji-kun?
Can I help you with something, Matsushita?
What's the matter?
Were you talking to the
chairman about something?
Apparently they want to remodel this area.
I happened to be here,
so he asked my opinion.
Oh? Is that it?
Hey, you gave the right answer during
that mental math test, right?
Q10
That subject just happens
to be one I'm good at.
I saw you and Hirata-kun
talking on the bench.
Hirata-kun's recovery didn't
just happen, did it?
Ayanokoji-kun, you're better at academics
and sports than you admit to, aren't you?
I hold back because I
don't want to stand out.
Then please contribute more
to the class from now on!
I want to reach Class A, too.
I'd recently been thinking
of doing that, actually.
But don't get your hopes up too high.
I'm already using 70 to 80
percent of what I have.
Okay.
And... can I ask you one thing?
Place a call to this number?
Cancel
Call
I want to ask you about Karuizawa-san.
Does she like you because she
knows what you can really do?
That's not why.
Then what is your relationship, exactly?
Place a call to this number?
Cancel
Call
What is it?
Since we're going for Class A, would you
be willing to unleash your full ability?
No.
Why not?
Unfortunately, there's no one in our
class year who can compete with me.
There's no point in me going all-out.
Let's put that to the test.
How?
How about competing with me in
our second-year written exams?
Ayanokoji Kiyotaka
If I win, you join the student council.
Could I ask why you want that?
I'll tell you when you lose.
I don't care for that.
In exchange, if I win,
you have to go all-out from then on.
I see.
I look forward to it.
See you later.
Place a call to this number?
Cancel
Call
So? What is it?
Did you remember what you wanted to tell me?
Slow down.
Like I said earlier, I've got
dinner with friends at seven.
Get it?
You have plenty of time.
This is creepy, okay?
You've been totally
wishy-washy since the café.
Oh, right!
And Sato-san is starting
to ask questions about us.
Matsushita is asking questions about us, too.
Huh? No way!
Matsushita's begun to
suspect my real abilities.
She seems like the type to hide her
own exceptional traits, as well.
H-Hang on a minute.
I can't keep up with all
this new information.
It feels like this is going
in a really bad direction.
I don't think we have to worry
about Sato and Matsushita.
No, we totally do!
If this gets around,
it's going to mess up all my plans.
Is it?
Even if I want to get a new boyfriend,
no one's going to ask me out if they
think I'm already with someone.
I broke up with Hirata-kun, remember?
So I'm looking for a new guy.
Is that a problem?
Of course not.
I mean, you're getting
close to Shiina-san, too!
And you've got stuff in
common with her, unlike me!
I'm leaving.
Kei.
What?!
Feel free to ignore this
if you don't like it.
Will you date me?
Huh?
I'm asking if you'd be willing to date me.
Um, but...
I don't understand...
what you're... talking... about?
Wait, huh? What?!
Y-You're joking, right?
I thought you liked Shiina-san—
I just did that to see if
you'd get jealous, I guess.
S-So? What the heck?
Why are you bringing this up now?
I wanted to prevent you from
becoming someone else's girlfriend.
So... Does that mean you...
You like me?
Yes. I like you, Karuizawa Kei.
I... I'm willing to date you.
Does that mean you like me, then?
Y-You're going to make me say it?
Yes, I am.
W-Well... I...
I guess I... might like you, too.
As much as I hate to admit it.
Hey!
A-Are you gonna kiss me or something?
No.
Not yet.
N-Not yet?
This is enough for now, isn't it?
Yeah... for now.
Hey. Have you gotten a little taller?
Maybe I have.
Humans are creatures that learn and grow.
This romance is necessary
for Karuizawa Kei to grow.
At the same time, I'll use
Kei to learn about romance.
That's something I couldn't
learn about in the White Room.
But once I'm done reading
the textbook known as Kei,
I won't need it anymore.
Or maybe...
I'll find myself in a future
where that's not the case.
Let's pray...
that in this moment,
holding someone precious in my arms...
that I'm smiling.